所以我们准备开始
so we're ready to start
处理请求
handling requests
我们需要一个可以定义的新模块
and we'll need a new module where we can define
这样做的功能
functions to do that
那么我们把这个模块文件放在哪里
so where do we put this module file
这就是约定的力量
well that's the power of conventions
我们不必随意决定
we don't have to arbitrarily decide
我们知道我们的应用程序代码位于 lib 目录中
we know our application code lives in the lib directory
按照惯例
and by convention
我们需要创建一个子目录
we need to create a subdirectory
在与项目同名的lib下
under lib with the same name as the project
所以我要在lib下新建一个文件夹
so I'm going to create a new folder under lib
我们项目的名称是服务
and the name of our project is service
所以我会有一个文件夹或
so I'm going to have a folder or
名为调查的目录
directory called survey
然后我们将我们的应用程序代码放入
and then we put our application code inside of
那个目录
that directory
所以在这里我要创建一个新文件
so here I'm going to create a new file
我们将称它为处理程序
we're going to call it handler
ex 和 this 否则我们将编写我们的第一个模块
ex and this or we'll write our first module
所以我们使用 def 模块
so we use def module
该模块的名称将是调查点
the name of this module is going to be survey dot
按照惯例
by convention
该模块的名称间隔在
the module is name spaced inside of the
请参阅与
see module which is the same as the
目录名称我们在 lib 中获得了我们的代码，请参见
directory name we've got our code inside of lib see
所以这里的模块将被调用
so the module here is going to be called
服务点，我们将其称为处理程序
serve dot and we're going to call it handler
好吧，让我们看第一个
okay so let's look at the first
我们要处理的http请求
http request we want to handle
现在我要把它粘贴进去
now I'm just going to paste this in
因为作为多行
because as multiple lines
你可以找到
and you can find
这些在代码包中，因此您可以将它们粘贴到
these in the code bundle so you can paste them into
如果你跟着
if you're following along
http请求有多行
http requests have multiple lines
所以我们使用了长生不老药
so we've used an elixir hair
码头
dock
这让我们可以跨多行格式化一个字符串
which lets us format a string across multiple lines
发坞以三重双引号开头
hair docks start with a triple double quote
然后是结尾的三重双引号
and then the ending triple double quote
必须在自己的线上
must be on its own line
因此，如果您不熟悉原始 http 请求
so if you're new to seeing a raw http request
它有三个部分
it has three parts
这里的第一部分称为他们的请求行
the first part here is called their request line
这是我们想要获取资源的方法
this is the method we want to get a resource
这是上路
this is the path upon
执行请求的对象
which to perform the request
所以我们得到了野生动物资源
so we're getting the wild things resource
然后这是他粒子
and then this is the he particle
那么第二部分是一个列表
then the second part is a list of
标头或键值对
headers or key value pairs
我们有钥匙，这里是主机
we have the key which is host here
然后值是示例
and then the value is example
com 所以这是被请求资源的主机
com so that's the host of the resource being requested
用户代理是软件
the user agent is the software
通常是发出请求的浏览器
typically a browser making the request
然后这个接受行指定媒体
and then this accept line specifies the media
响应可接受的类型
types acceptable for the response
在这种情况下，它是通配符，所以它基本上会接受
in this case it's wild card so it'll accept basically
任何事物
anything
那么这里有一个重要的空行
then there's an important blank line right here
分隔标题
separating the headers
来自可选的实际主体
from the actual body which is optional
我们这里没有尸体
we don't have a body here
但是主体通常用于传递表单参数
but a body is typically used to pass form parameters
我们会看到这样的身体，当我们
and we'll see a body like that when we
实际上稍后处理一个发布请求
actually handle a post request a bit later
这是我们想要发回的响应
and here's the response we want to send back
现在一个http响应也有三个部分
now an http response also has three parts
它从状态行开始
it starts with the status line
其中包括 http 版本
which includes the http version
在这种情况下状态码 200 然后是
the status code 200 in this case and then a
理由短语
reason phrase
然后我们有我们的响应头
then we have our response headers
这些又是键值对
these are again key value pairs
这是body的媒体类型
this one is the media type of the body
在这种情况下
in which case it's
文本 html 因为我们要发回 html
text html because we're sending back html
然后内容长度是正文的大小
and then content length is the size of the body
然后有一个空行分隔这些标题
then there's a blank line which separates those headers
从一个可选的身体
from an optional body
我们有一个身体
and we have a body
在这种情况下，因为我们要发回 html
in this case because we're sending back html
我们只是在老虎上发回熊线
and we're just sending back bears lines on tigers
现在我们正在使用动物和我们的领域
now we're using animals and our domain
只是为了让它有趣
just to make it fun
但有时人们希望例子更真实
but sometimes folks want examples to be more realistic
所以请随意替换
so please feel free to substitute in
产品或做事或
products or to dos or
任何让你觉得有趣的事
whatever feels fun for you
在您的回复正文中
in the body of your response
在高层次上，我们接下来需要处理这个请求
at a high level we need to handle this request next
所以让我们先写一个
so let's start by writing a
句柄函数
handle function
这将最终改变请求
that will ultimately transform the request
回应
to a response
我们将在我们的模块中做到这一点
we'll do that up in our module
我们将定义一个名为句柄的函数
we'll define a function called handle
它需要一个请求
it'll take a request
这将是请求字符串
that's going to be the request string
我们只是要离开那个身体
and we're just going to leave the body that
功能暂时空白
function blank for now
然后在模块本身的下方下方
then down below outside of the module itself
我们会继续打电话的
we'll go ahead and call that
我们可以说我们的反应将等于
we could say our response is going to be equal to
电话调查
calling survey
处理程序，即模块的名称
handler that's the name of the module
函数名是句柄
name of the function is handle
然后传入请求
and then pass in the request
我们有我们的要求在这里
we've got our request up here
存储在请求变量中
stored in the request variable
然后我们就打印
and then we'll just print
出去
out
io 给我们回复
io to put us the response
灵药真的有
elixir has really
改变了我对编程的看法
changed the way I think about programming
而不是考虑
instead of thinking about
对象和调用这些对象的方法来改变
objects and calling methods on those objects to change
他们现在的状态我认为更多的是
their state now I think more in terms of
用函数转换数据
transforming data with functions
在这种情况下，我们有一个要求
in this case we have a request
并通过一系列的转变
and through a series of transformations
我们想把它变成一个回应
we want to turn it into a response
这就是网络服务器所做的
and that's really what a web server does
我们的网络服务器将制作三个
and our web server is going to make three
高层转换
high level transformations
每个转换步骤都是一个函数
each transformation step will be a function
那么让我们来看看那些
so let's take a look at those
所以我要粘贴那些
so I'm going to paste in those
函数，所以我们可以专注于这个概念
functions so we can focus on the concept
不是语法
not the syntax
最初我们会回到语法
initially we'll come back to the syntax though
pars 函数转换请求环
the pars function transforms a request ring
成键值对
into a key value pair
现在这是一张长生不老药地图
now this is an elixir map
这类似于哈希和红宝石或
which is similar to a hash and ruby or an
javascript中的对象
object in javascript
我们将在下一节中查看详细信息
and we'll look at the details in the next section
我们只是设置了获取方法
we just set the method to get
削减野物的路径
the path to slash wild things
然后我们有一个响应体
and then we've got a response body which
开始只会是空的
starting off is just going to be empty
我们将这张地图称为对话
and we'll refer to this map as the conversation
因为它代表了一个非常
since it represents a very
浏览器和我们的服务器之间的简短对话
short conversation between a browser and our server
我们将简写为 come
and we'll just abbreviate it as come
显然
and obviously
我们将需要解析请求
we're going to need to parse the requesting
进入那张地图
into that map
然后路由函数转换该地图
the route function then transforms that map
进入一个新的地图，也有
into a new map that also has
响应体
a response body
所以如果我们看一下它的响应体
so if we look at the response body its bears
狮子和老虎
lions and tigers
因为这是对请求的适当响应
because that's the appropriate response for a request
愿意
to wiling
所以我们需要拿地图
so we're going to need to take the map
作为该函数的参数的 co 和 v
co and v that comes in as an argument to this function
接着
and then
还添加了一个响应主体，更多地填写了地图
also add a response body filling out the map even more
然后我们在这里有我们的格式响应函数
and then we have our format response function down here
现在它会采取最终的地图
now it's going to take the final map
那是作为参数出现的 co 和 v
that's co and v that's coming in as an argument
并改造它
and transform it
转换为有效的 http 响应字符串
into a valid http response string
所以我们需要获取值
so we're going to need to get the values
从地图中创建
from the map in order to create
这个响应字符串
this response string
所以因为我们里面已经有一个响应字符串
so because we've already got a response string inside
我们的格式响应函数在这里
of our format response function here
我只是要删除这个
I'm just going to remove this
预期的响应变量在这里
expected response variable down here
因为我们不需要它
because we don't need it
所以我们有转换函数
so we have the transformation functions
我们现在需要正确称呼他们
we now need to call them in the right
我们的句柄函数中的序列
sequence in our handle function
所以让我们依次看一下
so let's walk through this sequentially
我们将接受这个请求
we're going to take this request
ring 我们将把它传递给 parse
ring and we're going to pass it into parse
什么会回来
what's going to come back
是部分填充的地图
is a map that's partially filled out
我们称之为传达
we're going to call it convey
它缺少响应主体
it's missing a response body
然后我们想将该映射传递给路由函数
then we want to pass that map to the route function
这将填写响应正文
which is going to fill in the response body
我们想在 con 中捕获结果
and we want to capture the result of that in con
所以我们每次都在转换 con
so we're just transforming con each time through
这里填写更多数据
here filling out more data
然后最后我们想拿那张最终的地图
then finally we want to take that final map
并将其传递给格式化响应
and pass it to format response
这将基于生成我们的响应字符串
which will generate our response string based on
最终地图中有什么
what's in the final map
因为这是最后一次
and because this is the last
我们句柄函数中的表达式
expression in our handle function
该响应字符串将隐式返回
that response string will get implicitly returned
通过句柄函数
by the handle function
现在这将工作
now this will work
但是有一个更简洁的
but there's a more concise
和惯用的方式来表示这一点
and idiomatic way to represent this
使用 elixir 的管道运算符
using elixir's pipe operator
所以我只想评论这些
so I'm just going to comment these out
让我们将其表示为管道
and let's express this as a pipeline
我们将接受请求
we're going to take the request
将其导入解析函数
pipe it into the parse function
所以这里会发生什么
so what's going to happen here
请求是否会通过
is the request is going to get past
作为 parse 函数的参数
as an argument to the parse function which just has
一个参数，然后是该函数的结果
one argument then the result of that function
这是我们的对话地图
which is our conversation map
我们想将它传递给路由函数
we want to pass that to the route function
所以我们只是管它
so we just pipe that
再往里走一点
a little bit further into route
这将返回一张地图
that's going to return a map
我们最终想要传入的地图
our final map which we then want to pass into
格式响应
format response
所以在这样的管道中
so in a pipeline like this
左边函数的结果
the result of the function on the left
作为第一个通过
is passed as the first
右边函数的参数
argument to the function on the right
现在在这种特殊情况下
now in this particular case
我们所有的函数都只接受一个参数
all of our functions only take one argument
但请记住，它总是作为
but just remember that it's always passed as the
函数的第一个参数
first argument to the function
我们可以让它阅读更多
and we can make it read more
像一个转换步骤列表
like a list of transformation steps by
把每一步都放在自己的位置上
putting each step on its own line
就这样把它们放在那里
just put those down there like that
如果我运行它，就把它保存起来
save that away if I run it
我们看到了预期的反应
and we see the expected response
所以我们知道我们有
so we know that we've got
基本管道都设置好了
the basic pipeline all set up
所以我们在这里所做的是使用管道
so what we've done here is use a pipeline
基本上给我们一个大纲
to basically give us an outline of our program
或我们程序的外壳
or a shell of our program
这
the
我们想要完成的转型步骤
transformation steps that we want to take it through
我们在这里转换请求
we're transforming the request here
回应
into a response
这是最后一件事
which is the final thing
通过一系列显式变换
through a series of explicit transformations
通过将每个函数的结果传递到下一个
by piping the result of each function into the next
现在，如果你要做出改变
now if you're making a change
从面向对象编程到函数式编程
from oo programming to functional programming
最大的不同之一是学会思考
one of the big differences is learning to think
在转换数据方面
in terms of transforming data
我们会看到很多
and we're going to see a lot
在整个课程中更多的例子
more examples of this throughout the course up
接下来我们具体来看看如何解析
next we're specifically going to look at how to parse
请求字符串
the request string
进去
into them out